<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rust on TheSeaToad</title>
    <link>https://theseatoad.com/tags/rust/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rust on TheSeaToad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 20:03:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theseatoad.com/tags/rust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rust For Game Development #3 -- Game of Life</title>
      <link>https://theseatoad.com/rustforgamedevelopment3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 20:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theseatoad.com/rustforgamedevelopment3/</guid>
      <description>Prelude Follow along this tutorial using the cooresponding repository on Github. Snippets here will highlight important structs and methods, but for compiling code, refer to the link above.
This post is highlighing how the game logic and game state can be abstracted away from the rendering of the game. It is a good habit to decouple the code in this manner as it will be easier to iterate on either systems as well as writing tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust For Game Development #2 -- Simple cross-platform graphics</title>
      <link>https://theseatoad.com/rustforgamedevelopment2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 10:54:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theseatoad.com/rustforgamedevelopment2/</guid>
      <description>Prelude Follow along this tutorial using the cooresponding repository on Github. Snippets here will highlight important structs and methods, but for compiling code, refer to the link above.
This post will be all about graphics. Writing a game will not look like this in practice, unless you write your own engine. If this is enjoyable to you, maybe you can go about writing your own graphics engine. If not, there is plently of higher-level crates to leverage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust For Game Development #1 -- Rock Paper Scissors</title>
      <link>https://theseatoad.com/rustforgamedevelopment1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 20:35:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theseatoad.com/rustforgamedevelopment1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Games require two things:
Fast code It needs to be fast enough to render graphics and simulate physics all within one game tick. It needs to be able to support more complex mechanics, AI, and networking (for multiplayer games). It needs to be performant on a large range of devices that may have suboptimal hardware like consoles&amp;hellip;
Safe code It needs to support unloading and loading game objects frequently. It needs to load files from CDNs, disk, and cache.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
